Guide to the Kate Millett papers, 1912-2002, bulk 1951-2001 RL.10070
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Oversize Materials, 7 boxes, 21 folders
  - Oversize Boxes
    - Correspondence (CLOSED), 1972-1998
      - Literary Correspondence Subseries, 1998 (THESE MATERIALS ARE OPEN TO USE) (Box OS1)
        - 1998, Turkish newspaper clipping with photos (Box OS1)
      - Personal Correspondence Subseries (CLOSED UNTIL 2020), 1972-1976 (Box OS1)
    - Writings and Speeches, 1970-1986 and undated
      - Sexual Politics Subseries (Box OS1)
        - Galley Proofs, undated, 3 folders (Box OS1)
        - Reader's copy (page proofs), undated (Box OS1)
      - Flying Subseries (Box OS2)
        - Galleys, undated (Box OS2)
      - The Basement Subseries
        - Galleys, undated (Box OS2)
      - Speeches Subseries
        - 1982, Barnard conference on the politics of sexuality, North American Man-Boy Love Association (NAMBLA) newsletter (Box OS2)
      - Engagements Subseries
        - 1970 and undated, Engagements and offers (Box OS2)
        - 1978, Invitation to Australia (Box OS2)
        - 1983-1984 and undated, Gigs (Box OS2)
        - 1985-1986 and undated, Gigs (Box OS2)
      - Writings by Others Subseries (Box OS3)
        - Nancy Cott, Roots of Bitterness galleys, undated (Box OS3)
    - Subject Files, 1968-2002 and undated
      - Prisons Subseries (Box OS3)
        - Prisoners' Union, 1973 (Box OS3)
      - Psychiatric Survivors Movement Subseries
        - Foucault tribunal, German poster, 1998 (Box OS3)
        - "Little Library of Dangerous Thoughts," 1989 (Box OS3)
        - Psychiatric survivors movement, Oregon, 1991 and 1997 (Box OS3)
      - Torture Subseries
        - Human Rights Watch film festival, 1992 (Box OS3)
      - Women's Rights Movement Subseries
        - England, 1975-1981 (Box OS3)
        - Newsletters, 1968-1974 (Box OS3)
      - General Subject Files Subseries
        - Artists' Network for Mumia Abu-Jamal, 1998 (Box OS3)
        - Art shows, circa 1968-1969 (Box OS3)
        - Betty Friedan, How to Get the Women's Movement Moving Again, 1985 Nov. 3 (Box OS3)
        - Clara Fraser/ Freedom Socialist Party, 1987 (Box OS3)
        - Forum 98, 1997-1999 (Box OS8)
        - Impeachment - Stop the Inquisition, 1998-1999 (Box OS8)
        - "Interesting," 1974 (Box OS8)
        - Legendary Women Foundation, 1997 (Box OS8)
        - Midge MacKenzie film featuring Millett, correspondence and stills, 1970 (Box OS8)
        - Minneapolis Citizens against Pornography newsletter, 1984 (Box OS8)
        - New York University adjunct union drive, 2002 and undated (Box OS8)
        - Other women's colonies and women's festivals, 1988-1989 (Box OS8)
        - "Plans for Loft," 1989 (Box OS8)
        - Political activism, 1969-1970 (Box OS8)
        - Sun Valley Center for the Arts and Humanities, posters, 1977 (Box OS8)
        - Women's music festival brochures, undated (Box OS8)
    - Art Files, 1962-1994 and undated
      - Lesbian art sale, circa 1981 (Box OS8)
      - Silk screens correspondence, undated (Box OS8)
      - Fluxus posters, 1983-1993 (Box OS8)
      - Courtland Jessup Gallery, Provincetown, exhibition notes, circa 1991 (Box OS8)
      - Posters for shows by others, 1974-1994 and undated (Box OS8)
      - "Animal Doodles and Party Nonsense," 1962 and undated (Box OS4)
      - Doodles taken from sketchbook, undated (Box OS4)
      - Sketch books, undated, 3 folders (Box OS4)
      - Kate and Sophie's drawings, circa 1979 (Box OS5)
      - Gene Bonini, sketch of Millett, 1973 Feb. (Box OS5)
      - Mailing list, circa 1980 (Box OS5)
      - Shows by others, "Women/men on Men/women," 1990 (Box OS5)
      - Womanstyle Theatre Festival, "Small Mysteries" sculpture show, circa 1973 (Box OS5)
      - Alida Walsh poster and invitation, 1979 and undated (Box OS5)
      - Noho Gallery, "Elegy for Sita," notes, circa 1979-1980 (Box OS5)
      - Provincetown art scene, 1985 (Box OS5)
      - Puchang Gallery, Women by Women/Women by Men show brochure, 1990 (Box OS5)
    - Farm Papers, 1985-circa 1992
      - Correspondence Subseries (Box OS5)
        - 1985, Farm information requests, application materials (Box OS5)
      - Administrative Files Subseries
        - Circa 1992, Budget notes (Box OS5)
    - Course Materials, 1962
      - Teaching Material Subseries (Box OS5)
        - 1962, T.S. Eliot materials, Waseda (Box OS5)
    - Personal Files, 1984 and undated
      - Helen Millett Subseries (Box OS5)
        - undated, Independence News (Box OS5)
      - Other Personal Files Subseries
        - 1984, "FBI Follies" – Partisan Defense Committee (Box OS5)
    - Photographic Material, circa 1940s-1991 and undated
      - Circa 1940s, "Three sisters, Kate at 5, Dad, etc.," family photos and negatives (Box OS5)
      - 1970-1972 and undated, "Historic photos - Lesbian press conference and end of gay march to Albany" (Box OS5)
      - 1975 Nov., Virgil Giles, Paris-Match photography, Millett portraits (Box OS5)
      - 1975, Carin Drechsler-Marx, Millett and the new Bowery house (Box OS5)
      - 1975, Carin Drechsler-Marx, "Beautiful pics of the old Bowery house" (Box OS5)
      - 1977, Michiko Matsumoko, Millett at Los Angeles Women's Center (Box OS6)
      - Circa 1981, Cynthia MacAdams, "Birthday Suit Birthday Present," Millett portrait (Box OS6)
      - 1983, Faye Ellman, Millett portraits, "Tired Farmer Kate" (Box OS6)
      - Circa 1983, Michiko Matsumoto, Millett portraits (Box OS6)
      - 1987, Cynthia MacAdams, the Pyramids (Box OS6)
      - 1988, Bettina Flittner, Millett portraits (Box OS6)
      - 1989 Feb., Sophie Bassouls, Millett portraits, Paris (Box OS6)
      - 1991, Xenia, Contact sheets and prints of Millett portraits (Box OS6)
      - Undated, Cynthia MacAdams, Millett portraits, Provincetown (Box OS6)
      - Undated, Unidentified man (Box OS6)
      - Undated, Family portrait (Box OS6)
      - Undated, Wedding picture for unidentified Millett family member (Box OS6)
      - Undated, Diana Davies, Millett portrait (Box OS6)
    - Printed Materials, 1969-1994 and undated
      - 1969 Apr., Columbia Daily Spectator (Box OS6)
      - 1978 May 10, The Paris Metro with Millett interview (Box OS6)
      - Circa 1978, The Matriarchist with Millett speech excerpt (Box OS6)
      - 1988 Spring/Summer, National Mental Health Consumers' Association, Your Choice (Box OS6)
      - 1988, Vermont Liberation Organization, Counterpoint (Box OS6)
      - 1990 June, Lesbian News (Box OS6)
      - 1990 Spring/Summer, Eyeline: East Coast Contemporary Visual Arts (Fluxus article) (Box OS6)
      - 1990 Winter, Vermont Liberation Organization, Counterpoint, with Millett interview (Box OS6)
      - 1991 July-Aug., Minnesota Women's Press (Box OS6)
      - 1993 Jan., Sappho's Isle (Box OS6)
      - 1994 May, Dykespeak with Politics of Cruelty review (Box OS6)
      - 1972 June, Changes with Millett interview (Box OS7)
      - 1974 Nov. 27, The Miami Phoenix with article on Millett (Box OS7)
      - 1974-1975, Madness Network News (Box OS7)
      - 1975 Apr. and Aug., Majority Report (Box OS7)
      - 1975 Nov. 9, Ithaca New Times with Millett interview (Box OS7)
      - 1975 May, Plexus with Millett interview (Box OS7)
      - 1978-1980, The Militant (Box OS7)
      - 1979 Mar., Le Monde on Iran (Box OS7)
      - 1979 Mar.-Apr. and 1980 Feb., New Women's Times (Box OS7)
      - 1979 and 1986, Newspapers, Iran (Box OS7)
      - 1980 Mar., The Woman's Building, Spinning Off (Box OS7)
      - 1982 Fall-Winter, Madness Network News (Box OS7)
      - 1983 Feb. and Apr., Webspinner: Alberta Women's Newspaper (Box OS7)
      - 1989 May 1, Earth First! (Box OS7)
      - 1990 Sept., Womanews (Box OS7)
      - 1990-1992, Dendron (Box OS7)
      - 1991-1992, Prison News Service (Box OS7)
  - Oversize Folders
    - Correspondence, 1995
      ITEM IS OPEN TO RESEARCH.
      - 1995, Lisa Sheets, Shisa poster, National Computer Art Invitational, Eastern Washington University (Oversize-folder OF1)
    - Subject Files, 1958-circa 1998 and undated
      - Japan memorabilia - "Traditional Rural Potteries in Present Japan," rice paper poster, 1958 (Oversize-folder OF1)
      - Midge MacKenzie, me Tarzan you Jane performance art poster, 1970 (Oversize-folder OF1)
      - SisterSerpents, pro-choice poster and mailing, 1989 and undated (Oversize-folder OF1)
      - Psychiatric Survivors Movement: Israeli Association against Psychiatric Assault, poster, circa 1998 (Oversize-folder OF1)
      - Torture: "The Cross Is Not For Sale" exhibit, poster, 1986 (Oversize-folder OF1)
      - Travel: Paris, "En L'Absence du Peintre" film poster, 1985 (Oversize-folder OF1)
      - City Women event calendar, 1975 Dec. (Oversize-folder OF1)
      - Japan memorabilia, Sweet exhibition poster, 1963 (Oversize-folder OF1)
      - International Committee to Save Michael X, poster, circa 1973 (Oversize-folder OF1)
      - Women in Arms/Mujeres en Armas film poster, undated (Oversize-folder OF1)
      - Pornography protest posters [graphic sexual and violent content], undated (Oversize-folder OF1A)
      - Pornography protest posters [graphic sexual and violent content], 1984 and undated (Oversize-folder OF1B)
    - Art Files, 1974-1990 and undated
      - "Gloria Klein's Nice Poster," 1985 (Oversize-folder OF2)
      - Sun Valley Center for the Arts and Humanities, poster, 1977 (Oversize-folder OF2)
      - Lena Vandrey, toiles et gouaches poster, 1977 (Oversize-folder OF2)
      - New York Avante Garde Festival, poster, 1974 (Oversize-folder OF2)
      - New York Avante Garde Festival, poster, 1975 (Oversize-folder OF2)
      - Mildred Thompson, Years in Germany and After poster, 1990 (Oversize-folder OF2)
      - Millett, Nudes poster, undated (Oversize-folder OF2)
      - Millett, The Trial of Sylvia Likens poster, undated (Oversize-folder OF2)
      - Millett, Small Mysteries poster, 1976 (Oversize-folder OF2)
    - Personal Files, 1970
      - Loft Papers: 1970, Development proposals (map) (Oversize-folder OF2)
    - Documentary Film: Three Lives Series, 1972, 1980
      - 1972, Festival of Women's Films poster (Oversize-folder OF2)
      - 1980, German poster (Oversize-folder OF2)
    - Clippings, 1974
      - Nixon resignation (Italian news), 1974 (Oversize-folder OF3)
      - Iran clippings (Oversize-folder OF3)
    - Art
      - Suicide, 1979 (Oversize-folder 1-5)
      - Elegy for Sita (Oversize-folder 6-12)
      - After the French (Oversize-folder 13)
      - A.D. (Oversize-folder 14-16)
      - Freedom from Captivity (Oversize-folder 17-18)
- Artwork, 1975-1982 and undated; 27 boxes, 5 folders
  This collection of Kate Millett's artwork was received along with her other papers. The collection contains material put together in preparation for Millett's art exhibits (layout boards, cover notes, and photographs), ink drawings with texts, as well as a number of mounted paintings and sculptures.
  - U.S. Policy in Latin America, undated
    - Tall, heavy metal object in bubble wrap (17" x 120") (Box AW17)
    - Shirt missing left sleeve (Box AW25)
  - Fear of Flying, 1975
    Pages on film ready to print. Film attached to a single roll of cardboard with holes cut in the cardboard to frame each page
    - 10 sheets of proof pages (60" x 81") (Box AW7)
  - Nudes Under Glass, 1977
    - Ink drawing in unpainted wood frame signed 1/77 Bowery (35" x 23") (Box AW9)
  - The Lesbian Body, 1977
    These works were exhibited at the Levitan Gallery, NYC, in October of 1977. All materials are ink drawings except where otherwise noted.
    - untitled (35" x 23.5") (Box AW8)
    - "After All the Madness" (24.5" x 18.25") (Box AW9)
    - "Hopefully All the Times" on brown paper (24.25" x 18.25") (Box AW9)
    - "I Couldn't Look at Your" (26.5" x 19.5") (Box AW9)
    - "There Was Even One" (26.5" x 19.5") (Box AW9)
    - untitled on gray paper (26.5" x 20.25") (Box AW9)
    - untitled (29.5" x 23") (Box AW9)
    - "Rosie Between Your Picture" (23.25" x 18") (Box AW9)
    - "Laid back waiting" on orange paper (23.25" x 18.25") (Box AW9)
    - "I Knew Even Then" (21.5" x 20.25") (Box AW9)
    - "This Morning Was the First" (22" x 19") (Box AW9)
    - "All the Rivers" (22.75" x 19.75") (Box AW9)
    - Series of ink drawings with text, originally mounted together on orange cloth board (77.5" x 41") (Box AW26)
    - "Rosie it Ain't" (19" x 17.5") (Box AW26)
    - 2 Mounted photos, female nudes, by Cynthia McAdams (19.5" x 13.25") and (20.25" x 16.25") (Box AW26)
    - "The Last Afternoon" on brown paper (21" x 16") (Box AW26)
    - "Belly of a 3 Year-Old" (22.5" x 17.5") (Box AW26)
    - "I Was Surprised" (23" x 16") (Box AW26)
  - The Trial of Sylvia Likens, 1978
    This art installation inspired by an infamous murder trial depicts a courtroom scene with the five defendants. Millett's book "The Basement" also deals with this case.
    - Sylvia: torso with head, arms, wig, coat, legs and socks; Paula: legs and stockings; Gertrude: torso, legs and socks (Box AW1)
    - Ricky: torso; Coy: torso (Box AW2)
    - Gertrude: arms and torso; Paula: arms and torso (Box AW3)
    - Coy: legs; Ricky: legs and socks (Box AW4)
    - Metal flagpole packed with bubble wrap (54" height (Box AW5)
    - Johnnie: torso, legs and socks; Ricky: legs and socks (Box AW6)
    - Basement Court Scene, Particle board with face cutouts (33.5" x 25"); Trial/crime scene materials on matboard (30.5" x 24.25"); mounted photos (24.25" x 18.25") (Box AW8)
    - Basement Court Scene, "Full house for torture death hearing" wood panel (85" x 53.5") (Box AW12)
    - Tablecloth; 2 ornate wooden furniture pieces (29" x 23" x 7"); 1 wooden furniture piece (25" x 24" x 3.5") (Box AW13)
    - Basement Court Scene, Gertrude portrait on wood panel (55" x 41") (Box AW14)
    - Basement Court Scene, wood panel (42" x 41.5") (Box AW15)
    - Basement Court Scene, "Packed court at trial" wood panel (42" x 41.5") (Box AW16)
    - Basement, trial materials on foam board with photocopies (36" x 36") (Oversize-folder 19)
    - Sylvia: jeans and shoes (Box AW19)
    - Johnnie: suit jacket, trousers, shirt, necktie, shoes, face, hands (Box AW20)
    - Coy: suit jacket, trousers, shirt, necktie, shoes, socks, face, hands (Box AW21)
    - Ricky: suit jacket, trousers, shirt, necktie, shoes, 3 faces, hands (Box AW22)
    - Gertrude: dress, cardigan, shoes, face, hands (Box AW23)
    - Paula: jacket, skirt, shoes, face, hands (Box AW24)
    - Sawhorses (Box AW30-31)
  - An Elegy for Sita, 1979
    These materials are from the exhibit An Elegy for Sita, which differs from Millett's book of the same name.
    - Photos of Sita with text, "I waited to see" (24.5" x 20.24"); Photos of Millett with text (40" x 23.75"); Photomantage with text (39" x 31.25") and (37.24" x 24.75") (Box AW8)
    - "Your Voice, Sita" (30" x 22"); Ink drawing (34.5" x 26.25") (Box AW9)
    - Ink drawing (51" x 48") (Box AW10)
      This item is restricted and requires approval by curatorial staff before use. Item should be unpacked in the staff workroom with curatorial or conservation assistance before being served to the patron in the reading room. Contact Conservation for unpacking or repacking assitance if needed.
    - Photos of Sita with text on black paper (90.5 x 47.25") (Box AW11)
    - Photomantage with text, "There was just one roll" (38.5" x 33") (Oversize-folder 20)
    - Photomantage with text, "As if the photographs" (38.5" x 33") (Oversize-folder 20)
    - Dead, so dead you looked (38.5" x 33") (Oversize-folder 20)
    - Text explaining Elegy for Sita exhibit (41" x 22.5") (Oversize-folder 19)
    - Ink drawing with text, "Dying the body" (44.6" x 26.5") (Oversize-folder 21)
    - Mounted pages from Elegy book on black paper (47.5" x 14.5") (Oversize-folder 19)
    - Mounted poem, "I Make Mistakes" (49" x 30.5") (Oversize-folder 22)
    - Ink drawing, "Better than Beatrice" (50.25" x 26.25") (Oversize-folder 21)
    - Ink drawing, "Two Years Later" (50.25" x 24.25") (Oversize-folder 21)
    - Ink drawing, "The Long Philosophic" (50.25" x 26.25") (Oversize-folder 21)
    - Ink drawing, "Dead, Dead, Dead" (50.25" x 30.25") (Oversize-folder 23)
    - Ink drawing, "Acceptance" (51" x 39") (Oversize-folder 23)
    - Ink drawing, "The Shade" (51" x 39") (Oversize-folder 23)
    - Ink drawing, untitled (51" x 39") (Oversize-folder 22)
    - Ink drawing, "Sure of Some Return" (51" x 39") (Oversize-folder 22)
    - Series of ink drawings with text, originally mounted on orange cloth board (47" x 43") (Box AW26)
  - Ink Drawings, 1977-1982 and undated
    - "But What if You Came" (25.25" x 19.25") (Box AW9)
    - "Even Then, That Moment" on cream paper (26" x 20") (Box AW9)
    - "Hours Now Only Hours" (25.25" x 19.25") (Box AW9)
    - untitled (30" x 22") (Box AW9)
    - untitled, signed "1/77 Bowery" (31" x 25.5") (Box AW9)
    - "Tulip Cunt" medium sumi ink, 1982 (32.25" x 24.25") (Box AW9)
    - "That Afternoon, the Last Time" on gray paper (23" x 17.5") (Box AW26)
    - "Laid Back Waiting" on gray paper (23.5" x 17.5") (Box AW26)
    - "What is it Like" (23.25" x 18") (Box AW26)